<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>a dystopian journey into the heart of tech</title><link>https://1x-eng.github.io/blog/</link><description>Recent content on a dystopian journey into the heart of tech</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Jul 2023 20:07:09 +1000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://1x-eng.github.io/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Database Is Sacred</title><link>https://1x-eng.github.io/blog/posts/database-is-sacred/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Jul 2023 20:07:09 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://1x-eng.github.io/blog/posts/database-is-sacred/</guid><description>Database is Sacred: An &amp;ldquo;Engineer&amp;rsquo;s&amp;rdquo; Testament What does the word &amp;lsquo;database&amp;rsquo; make you think of? It&amp;rsquo;s probably difficult to generalize, but I&amp;rsquo;m guessing a good chunk of you would think of a &amp;lsquo;relational&amp;rsquo; flavor. Well, there&amp;rsquo;s no shortage of &amp;lsquo;flavors&amp;rsquo; among databases today, and I feel like talking — or venting — about how often relational databases are used beneath their potential today
(Relational) Databases are awesome My (not so distant) future self will probably negate this title😁, but for the purpose of this blog or the context in my head today, yes - relational databases are awesome.</description></item><item><title>We Have a Problem</title><link>https://1x-eng.github.io/blog/posts/we-have-a-problem/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Apr 2022 17:40:27 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://1x-eng.github.io/blog/posts/we-have-a-problem/</guid><description>The Reality of Imaginary Problems - In the context of Software Many factors lead to ineffective software development: from the tools used, to team communication, to the personal motivation of developers, the testing approach to the organisational leadership matrix. Among these, there&amp;rsquo;s a fundamental issue that often results in poorly conceived software: chasing perceived or, more often than not, non-existent problems, that take shape through the process to prove some kinda relevance by one or many involved directly or indirectly in the process.</description></item><item><title>Pipelines</title><link>https://1x-eng.github.io/blog/posts/pipelines/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2020 10:42:18 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://1x-eng.github.io/blog/posts/pipelines/</guid><description>Serverless Data Pipelines: AWS Glue is a potential future poster figure; maybe not just yet! Data engineering plays a pivotal role in the success of organizations, especially those that are data-driven. It can make or break an organization&amp;rsquo;s growth. Data pipelines form the foundation of data engineering. However, the term &amp;ldquo;pipeline&amp;rdquo; has become somewhat clichéd in software engineering, as it can mean different things depending on the context and significance of the tasks involved.</description></item><item><title>Logs</title><link>https://1x-eng.github.io/blog/posts/logs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Jun 2020 10:40:03 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://1x-eng.github.io/blog/posts/logs/</guid><description>Centralized logging &amp;amp; log analytics in a busy, distributed environment Logs play a crucial role in any system, providing valuable insights into your application&amp;rsquo;s behavior, system activities, and the causes of errors. It is essential to efficiently monitor these logs to ensure your system is functioning as expected. In case something goes wrong, you need to quickly identify the issue, understand what happened, and take preventive measures to avoid its recurrence.</description></item><item><title>Ethereact</title><link>https://1x-eng.github.io/blog/posts/ethereact/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2019 10:44:56 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://1x-eng.github.io/blog/posts/ethereact/</guid><description>ETHEReact: Build a Full Stack Decentralized E-Commerce App, Deploy to Ethereum Virtual Machine &amp;amp; Interact using ReactJS TL;DR This article is not an in-depth explanation of Blockchain or a marketing pitch for Crypto.
Instead, this article is intended to guide developers and blockchain enthusiasts in building an end-to-end prototype on the blockchain. By the end of this article, you will have constructed a basic decentralized e-commerce platform.
Throughout the article, you will write two contracts in Solidity (one for the supplier and another for the customer), compile and migrate your contract to the EVM (Ethereum Virtual Machine), create a simple ReactJS frontend, and connect your frontend to the EVM using web3.</description></item></channel></rss>