<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>a dystopian journey into the heart of tech</title><link>https://1x-eng.github.io/blog/</link><description>Recent content on a dystopian journey into the heart of tech</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Jul 2023 20:07:09 +1000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://1x-eng.github.io/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Database Is Sacred</title><link>https://1x-eng.github.io/blog/posts/database-is-sacred/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Jul 2023 20:07:09 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://1x-eng.github.io/blog/posts/database-is-sacred/</guid><description>Database is Sacred: An &amp;ldquo;Engineer&amp;rsquo;s&amp;rdquo; Testament What does the word &amp;lsquo;database&amp;rsquo; make you think of? It&amp;rsquo;s probably difficult to generalize, but I&amp;rsquo;m guessing a good chunk of you would think of a &amp;lsquo;relational&amp;rsquo; flavor. Well, there&amp;rsquo;s no shortage of &amp;lsquo;flavors&amp;rsquo; among databases today, and I feel like talking — or venting — about how often relational databases are used beneath their potential today
(Relational) Databases are awesome My (not so distant) future self will probably negate this title😁, but for the purpose of this blog or the context in my head today, yes - relational databases are awesome.</description></item><item><title>We Have a Problem</title><link>https://1x-eng.github.io/blog/posts/we-have-a-problem/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Apr 2022 17:40:27 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://1x-eng.github.io/blog/posts/we-have-a-problem/</guid><description>The Reality of Imaginary Problems - In the context of Software Many factors lead to ineffective software development: from the tools used, to team communication, to the personal motivation of developers, the testing approach to the organisational leadership matrix. Among these, there&amp;rsquo;s a fundamental issue that often results in poorly conceived software: chasing perceived or, more often than not, non-existent problems, that take shape through the process to prove some kinda relevance by one or many involved directly or indirectly in the process.</description></item></channel></rss>